Welcome to you into the process of learning the Python Programming Language !

Python is a high-level programming language, with applications in numerous fields - including web programming,
 scripting, scientific computing, and artificial intelligence fields with many other tasks uses python language.

It is (Python) very popular and used by organizations such as Google, NASA, the CIA, and Disney.
Python program code is processed at runtime by the interpreter. There is no need to compile your program before 
executing it.

পাইথন প্রোগ্রামিং ভাষা শেখার প্রক্রিয়াতে আপনাকে স্বাগতম!

পাইথন একটি উচ্চ স্তরের প্রোগ্রামিং ভাষা, অনেক ক্ষেত্রে অ্যাপ্লিকেশন সহ - ওয়েব প্রোগ্রামিং, স্ক্রিপ্টিং, বৈজ্ঞানিক কম্পিউটিং, এবং কৃত্রিম বুদ্ধিমত্তা ক্ষেত্রগুলি সহ অন্যান্য অনেকগুলি কাজ পাইথন ভাষা ব্যবহার করে।

এটি (পাইথন) খুব জনপ্রিয় এবং গুগল, নাসা, সিআইএ এবং ডিজনি প্রতিষ্ঠানগুলির দ্বারা ব্যবহৃত হয়।
পাইথন প্রোগ্রাম কোড ইন্টারপ্রেটার দ্বারা রানটাইম এ প্রক্রিয়া করা হয়। এটি কার্যকর করার আগে আপনার প্রোগ্রাম কম্পাইল করার প্রয়োজন নেই।

Welcome into Python learning!

The three major versions of Python are 1.x, 2.x and 3.x. These are subdivided into minor versions, 
such as 2.7 and 3.3.
Code written for Python 3.x is guaranteed to work in all future versions. 
Both Python Version 2.x and 3.x are used currently. 
This course covers Python 3.x, but it isn't hard to change from one version to another.

Python has several different implementations, written in various languages. 
The version used in this course, CPython, is the most popular by far.
An interpreter is a program that runs scripts written in an interpreted language such as Python.


পাইথন শেখার মধ্যে স্বাগতম!

পাইথনের তিনটি প্রধান সংস্করণ 1.x, 2.x এবং 3.x। এইগুলিকে 2.7 এবং 3.3 হিসাবে ছোটখাট সংস্করণে উপবিভাজিত করা হয়।
পাইথন 3.x জন্য লেখা কোড ভবিষ্যতে সংস্করণে কাজ করার জন্য নিশ্চিত।
পাইথন সংস্করণ 2.x এবং 3.x উভয় বর্তমানে ব্যবহার করা হয়।
এই কোর্স পাইথন 3.x জুড়ে রয়েছে, তবে এক সংস্করণ থেকে অন্য সংস্করণে পরিবর্তন করা কঠিন নয়।

পাইথন বিভিন্ন ভাষার মধ্যে বিভিন্ন বিভিন্ন বাস্তবায়ন আছে।
এই কোর্সে ব্যবহৃত সংস্করণ, সিপিথন, এ পর্যন্ত সবচেয়ে জনপ্রিয়।
একটি ইন্টারপ্রেটার/অনুবাদক এমন একটি প্রোগ্রাম যা পাইথন এর মত ব্যাখ্যা করা ভাষাতে লিখিত স্ক্রিপ্টগুলি চালায়।
??????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????????

