Functions & Modules
Comments & Docstrings

Comments

Comments are annotations to code used to make it easier to understand. They don't
 affect how code is run. 
In Python, a comment is created by inserting an octothorpe (otherwise known as a 
number sign or hash symbol: #). All text after it on that line is ignored.
For example:
x = 365
y = 7
# this is a comment

print(x % y) # find the remainder
# print (x // y)
# another comment


Result:
>>>
1
>>>

Python doesn't have general purpose multiline comments, as do programming languages such as C.

Docstrings

Docstrings (documentation strings) serve a similar purpose to comments, as they are designed to explain code. However, they are more specific and have a 
different syntax. They are created by putting a multiline string containing an explanation of the function below the function's first line.
def shout(word):
  """
  Print a word with an
  exclamation mark following it.
  """
  print(word + "!")
    
shout("spam")


Result:
>>>
spam!
>>>

Unlike conventional comments, docstrings are retained throughout the runtime of the program. This allows the programmer to inspect these comments at run time.

